Adam Carpenter

Software Developer

adamcarpenter86@gmail.com

303.918.2290

in adam-joseph-carpenter

Adamj1232

Personal Website

SKILLS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Terminal
Atom/VS Code
Agile Development
HTML5
CSS3/SASS
JavaScript – ES6
jQuery
Typescript/RxJS

Angular 2/4/5 Material Design

React/Router/Redux

Responsive Design NodeJS/ExpressJS

RethinkDB

TDD

Mocha

Chai

Selenium/Protractor

Enzyme

Jest

ADDITIONAL

Project Management
Graphic Design
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Illustrator
Telecommunications Cabling
Home and Business Security
Data Center Rack & Stack
Event Planning
Microsoft Office

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software + Design.

01-2017 - 07-201

Front End Web Development

Mentor to current student body

SUMMARY

After 3 years in telecommunications and 10 in the music industry, I became a software developer. I graduated early to join the Advanced Engineering Team at the second-largest cable-operating company in the country. As an integral member of the UI development team, I deployed features to simplify, enhance and automate network software for network engineers nationwide. I'm a talented software developer seeking experience developing useful products and solution for forward-thinking teams and organizations.

PROJECTS

Symphony

- Enterprise software built with Angular 2/4/5 leveraging Typescript, RxJS, AgGrid, D3, Material Design, Express Gateway, and more.
- Created an internal ticketing and alert system, network visualization and troubleshooting tool and portal allowing network engineers to run troubleshooting and configuration commands and scripts on customized groups of devices across the country.
- Simplified and enhanced visual and troubleshooting aspects of a nation-wide network;
 accessible by various devices from many vendors.

Website: Enterprise Software – See portfolio for GIF example

GigWrangler

- React/Redux JS app developed to allow musicians to connect with music venues across the country.
- Utilized Google Maps API, Google Map Clustering, and tested with Mocha and Enzyme,
- Created custom data-set of 3300+ music venues throughout the US using a Python web scraper and Google maps API to visibly pinpoint locations.

Website: https://adamj1232.github.io/Gig-Wrangler/
GitHub Repo: https://github.com/Adamj1232/Gig-Wrangler

CloudKicker/RAIngULAR

- Responsive weather app built in both ReactJS and Angular2, tested with Mocha and Enzyme.
- Employs the Weather Underground API to render fully accessible on demand weather forecasts as well as an auto-complete city/state search for smooth UX.
- RAIngULAR is a slightly simplified version of CloudKicker built using Angular2.

Website: https://adamj1232.github.io/CloudKicker-WeatherForecast-ReactProject/

Website: https://adamj1232.github.io/RAIngular/

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/Adamj1232/CloudKicker-WeatherForecast-ReactProject

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/Adamj1232/RAIngular

EXPERIENCE

Charter Communications – Advanced Engineering

FEB 2007 - FEB 2016

Software Engineer / UI Engineer — Englewood, CO

- Worked as an integral part of the UI team in the AE dept.
- Responsible for creating enterprise software for internal usage by operations and network engineers
- UI/UX development, automated testing and interface driven network automation as well as development of the API Gateway and data modeling.

RossComm JUL 2013 - DEC 2016

Lead Low Voltage Technician — Westminster, CO

- Responsible for installing, troubleshooting and training on large workstation projects.
- Lead a team on large scale telephone, security and server-room installations